faniq.com 2013-12-03

# FanIQ - Privacy Policy

**Effective Date: June 5, 2012**

FanIQ ("FanIQ" or "we") respects and values your privacy. As such, this Privacy Policy details FanIQ's treatment of personally identifiable information ("PII") and other information collected through the website, located at [www.FanIQ.com](http://www.faniq.com/), any related online applications or services, or the mobile versions thereof (collectively, "Website").

FanIQ reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted on this website and the effective date of the Privacy Policy will be modified to reflect the effective date of the most recent version. If a material change to our information practices occurs in the future, we will only use PII collected from the time of the policy change forward for these new purposes unless we have your consent. 

The terms and conditions governing your use of the FanIQ website are contained in a separate Terms of Use agreement available at www.FanIQ.com/terms.php. 

### Types of Information We Collect or Maintain About Individuals Through This Website

### Personally Identifiable Information 

PII is information that allows FanIQ to identify and communicate with you.

We have designed the FanIQ website so that you can view the website without providing FanIQ with any PII or having a FanIQ account. This type of user is known as a Visitor.

Certain activities on the FanIQ website, such as sending messages, creating a personal profile, and more, require you to create an account with FanIQ. This type of user is known as a Registered User. To create an account, you must register as a Registered User and FanIQ may collect or maintain the following PII about you:

First and last name; physical address; email address; mobile phone number; gender; age; education; occupation; photographs; personal interests; hometown; favorite teams; blog URL; and any other PII you submit during the course of normal correspondence (including SMS, MMS and email) with FanIQ (collectively "Profile Information").

During your use of FanIQ, you may set up your personal profile, form relationships, send messages, initiate fan actions, perform searches and queries, form groups, set up events, add applications, and transmit information through various channels. We collect and retain this data to enable you to view prior actions and messages. We may combine this PII with information from other sources. By creating an account and providing FanIQ your mobile phone number, you expressly agree that FanIQ may contact you by SMS (i.e. "text") message or Multimedia Messaging Service (MMS). If you send information to FanIQ via SMS or MMS, FanIQ may respond to you via SMS or MMS.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Information 

Non-personally identifiable information is information FanIQ collects in the normal course of operating the FanIQ website that does not reveal the specific identity of the individual. We collect certain aggregate and non-personal information when you visit this website. This information does not relate to a single identifiable visitor. 

When you visit the website to browse, read or download information, we automatically collect standard computer information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring website addresses. We generally do not link standard computer information to anything that will allow us to identify users unless to enforce compliance with our rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, users or others. 

We also may collect aggregate and non-personal information through "Cookies" or other website technology as explained below.

### How We Use PII Collected on the FanIQ Website

### Individual PII Collected on the FanIQ Website 

FanIQ is intended to be a global community for discussion around sports. Accordingly, the FanIQ website publicly displays some Profile Information, including a Registered User's pictures, name, username, age, hometown, and location (country and city) to facilitate user interaction on the FanIQ website. 

We use Registered User's email addresses to share content and to notify you of important updates to the Privacy Policy or Terms of Use. We do not share with, or display to, other website users a Registered User's email address or mobile phone number. To facilitate searching and finding friends and acquaintances on the FanIQ website, FanIQ allows users to search for other Registered Users as well as invite new users via E-mail addresses. If you choose to use our invitation service to tell a friend about FanIQ, we will ask you for information needed to send the invitation, such as your friend's E-mail address. We will send your friend an E-mail in your name inviting him or her to visit FanIQ, and may send up to three (3) reminders. FanIQ stores this information to send invitations and reminders, to register a friend connection if your invitation is accepted, to allow you to see the invitations you have sent, and to track the success of our referral program. FanIQ does not sell these E-mail addresses. If you were contacted this way and would like to be removed from our database, you may send us a request and we will do so within a reasonable period of time.

We may also use a Registered User's email address or mobile phone number to send email, SMS and MMS updates or news, such as an email newsletter, regarding the FanIQ website or other services and products that may be of interest to Registered Users. You may opt out of such E-mails by changing your user preferences. FanIQ may also send you service-related announcements from time to time through the general operation of the service. FanIQ reserves the right to send you notices about your account even if you opt out of all voluntary E-mail notifications.

In some cases, other FanIQ users may be able to supplement your profile (eg. Initiating fan actions, commenting on your blog, giving you gifts, etc.) As with other websites, your profile information may be made available to third party search engines. FanIQ allows for the RSS syndication of its public content and may allow third parties to access publicly available FanIQ content through an application programming interface (API). However, all FanIQ user passwords will be kept strictly private.

We may create anonymous records from PII by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to you. We may use this anonymous information to analyze request and usage patterns to improve the website and our services. We reserve the right to use and disclose this anonymous information to third parties for various purposes, including for internal business analysis and to provide aggregate demographic data to our partners.

Users can also login to the FanIQ website using their Facebook username and password through Facebook Connect or such other services as we may make available for login from time to time. Information provided to Facebook will be subject to Facebook's privacy policy. Once a user logs in with a Facebook username and password, certain PII will be shared with FanIQ. We will treat this shared information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Sharing of Individual PII with Third Parties

FanIQ will not sell, rent or lease PII collected on the FanIQ website to third-party marketers. FanIQ, may however, share PII with its affiliates (FanIQ is a subsidiary of PulsePoint, Inc.) who may use the information for marketing purposes. For more information, please see the PulsePoint, Inc. Privacy Policy [here](http://www.datranmedia.com/privacy/). Our affiliates will not share PII with unaffiliated third parties for their own marketing purposes. 

FanIQ may share PII with service providers who assist us with our marketing efforts and other communications, but those service providers will not use this PII for their own marketing purposes and are prohibited by contract from sharing this PII with any party other than FanIQ. These businesses include providers of website applications. These services enable us to deliver communications to website users and to verify and update information about website users.

If you use any third party applications developed for FanIQ, applications may access and share certain information about you with others in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Before allowing any third party applications on FanIQ, we require the third party partner to enter into an agreement with us which requires them to respect your privacy and strictly limits their collection, use, and storage of your information. However, while we have undertaken contractual and technical steps to restrict possible misuse of such information by such third party partners, we cannot and do not guarantee that all third party partners will abide by such agreements. In addition, third party partners may require you to sign up to their own terms of service, privacy policies, or other policies, which may give them additional rights or impose additional obligations on you. Please be sure to review these terms and policies carefully before using any third party partners of FanIQ.

FanIQ, or a partner, may sponsor a promotion, sweepstakes, or contest on www.FanIQ.com. Users may be asked to provide personal information, including name, E-mail address, or home address, or to answer questions in order to participate. We may transfer personal information to certain advertising partners that you have explicitly requested to receive information from. It will be clear at the point of collection who is collecting the personal information and whose privacy statement will apply.

FanIQ may also share PII in the following limited circumstances: (1) upon receipt of a properly authorized and authenticated governmental request for information; (2) in response to a subpoena or a court order; (3) to comply with relevant laws; (4) in response to an investigation of fraud regarding a specific individual; (5) in an effort to safeguard the person or property of an FanIQ employee or a third party; or (6) when FanIQ believes it is necessary to protect our interests or we believe in good faith that the law requires the sharing of your PII. 

Finally, FanIQ may, in the future, decide to sell, merge or otherwise reorganize its business. FanIQ reserves the right to transfer and disclose PII in this circumstance, but data collected by FanIQ will be governed by the same privacy policy that existed prior to any change in business conditions unless you consent to the new privacy policy.

### How We Use Non-Personally Identifiable Information Collected on the FanIQ Website

We use non-personally identifiable information to help us to tailor the features, performance and support of our products and services to website users; to offer you additional information and opportunities; and to inform you of changes to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use of the website. The non-personally identifiable information we collect may be shared with FanIQ's affiliates and third parties to provide you with more relevant services and advertisements to website users, including advertisements relating to FanIQ on other websites you may visit.

### How We Use Cookies on the FanIQ Website

Cookies are pieces of information that any website may transfer to your browser that are then stored in your computer's system. Cookies are returned to the website that deposited them when a visitor returns to that site. We use Cookies to store users' preferences and to record session information. We also use Cookies for purposes including ensuring that users are not repeatedly offered the same advertisements and to customize newsletter, advertising and web page content based on browser type and user profile information. The deposit of Cookies by the website may enhance your online experience by allowing us to save your preferences for your next visit. Our Cookies may also measure the general activity on the website and measures advertising effectiveness, which allows us to determine which areas and features are most popular. This information allows us to make improvements to our website.

Most web browsers are set up to accept cookies. You can, however, reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you choose to decline Cookies, some of the functionality of the website may be impaired. Some of the cookies placed may be from our affiliate PulsePoint, Inc's Aperture business. For more information, please see the PulsePoint, Inc. [Aperture privacy policy](http://www.datranmedia.com/privacy/aperture/). Should you wish to opt-out of us placing an Aperture audience cookie on your browser, you can [click here](http://rt.displaymarketplace.com/optout.html) to deploy an "opt-out" cookie on your browser. This cookie, when installed on your browser, will prevent us from placing a new Aperture audience cookie on that browser and will prevent the Aperture audience business from collecting web data and audience data on that browser.

Web beacons, also known as "clear gifs," "one-pixel gifs," "web bugs," "Internet tags" or "pixel tags," are small graphic images on a website or in an email that allow us and third parties to monitor the activity on our website or to make Cookies more effective. We use log files to store the data that is collected through web beacons.

### Third Party Advertising 

Ads appearing on the FanIQ website may be delivered to you by FanIQ or its affiliates or by one of FanIQ' web advertising partners or advertising networks. FanIQ may allow third-party advertisers or advertising networks that will present advertisements on some of our pages to set and access their Cookies on your computer. These Cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad servers may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked on. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisement that they believe will be of most interest to you. Advertisers' use of Cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy.

The Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), a self-regulatory organization consisting of online advertising networks, has an opt-out tool that allows you to opt out of the data collection and targeted ad programs of NAI members. You may access the NAI opt-out tool here. PrivacyChoice's opt-out tool allows you to opt out of other third parties (in addition to NAI members) who may place cookies on your computer. To opt out of these third parties, please go to <http://www.privacychoice.org/choose>.

### Choice

Access and control over most personal information on FanIQ is readily available through the profile editing tools. You may modify or delete any of your profile information at any time by logging into you're your account. Information edited this way will be updated immediately. If you wish to deactivate your account, you may do so at any time. Removed information may persist in backup copies for a reasonable period of time but will not be generally available to FanIQ users. For a more detailed description of FanIQ's policy on removed information, please [click here](http://www.faniq.com/terms.php) to see FanIQ's Terms of Service.

When you make use of FanIQ's communications features to share information with others on FanIQ, such as sending a personal message to another FanIQ user, you generally cannot remove such communications.

Recipients of invitations from FanIQ may contact FanIQ using the contact information below under "Access" to request removal of their information from our database.

### Security

We endeavor to safeguard and protect our users' information. When users submit information on our website, such information is protected both online and offline. The servers in which we store PII are kept in a secure physical environment. FanIQ has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under our control. Please be advised that, although we take reasonable technological precautions to protect your data, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Therefore, FanIQ cannot warrant that your information will be absolutely secure. Any transmission of data at or through our website is at your own risk. However, access to your information is strictly limited, and not accessible to the public.

### Links

FanIQ may contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Website to review the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by FanIQ.

### Children's Privacy

FanIQ places the highest value on the privacy of children. FanIQ does not knowingly collect PII from children under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. 

### Access 

Individuals wishing to review PII collected by FanIQ on this website should write to FanIQ Privacy Department, c/o PulsePoint, Inc., 345 Hudson Street, 5th Floor, New York, New York, 10014. FanIQ may take reasonable steps to confirm the identity of the consumer in an effort to prevent identity theft.

### European Union and Other Non-US Residents

Your information may be stored and processed in any country in which FanIQ or its affiliates maintain facilities, including in the United States, which may not have protections equivalent to those in your home country. For purpose of providing the service or sharing or disclosing data for purposes noted in this policy, FanIQ reserves the right to transfer information outside of your country. By using and registering on the FanIQ website, you consent to the transfer of information outside of your country.

In addition, FanIQ's parent company, PulsePoint, Inc., has self certified to the Department of Commerce's Safe-Harbor framework, and we adhere to the Safe-Harbor Principles. For more information on the Safe-Harbor program, visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor>. If you are a European resident and have a data-privacy inquiry, you may contact us at [info@pulsepoint.com](mailto:info@pulsepoint.com) or in writing at:

PulsePoint, Inc.  
345 Hudson Street, 5th Floor  
New York, NY 10014  
Tel: (212) 706-9781

If your data privacy inquiry was not satisfactorily resolved by us then you may contact the DMA Safe Harbor Program at:

Safe Harbor Line  
Direct Marketing Association  
1615 L Street, NW - Suite 1100  
Washington, DC 20036  
Fax: 202-955-0085  
Telephone: 202-861-2410  
Email: [safeharbor@the-dma.org](mailto:safeharbor@the-dma.org)

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who have provided PII to PulsePoint, Inc. or its partners to request certain information regarding FanIQ disclosure of PII to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Within thirty days of receiving such a request, we will provide a list of the categories of PII disclosed to third parties for third-party direct marketing purposes during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of the third parties when required. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve our right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified in this section.

If you have any questions about your California privacy rights or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at feedback@FanIQ.com or in writing at:

FanIQ Privacy Department  
c/o PulsePoint, Inc.  
20 Broad Street  
6th Floor  
New York, NY 10005  
Tel: (212) 706-9781
